<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>MozillaTN</title>
    <description>Mozilla Tamilnadu Community Website, highlights more about contributors contribution and tutorials to get started with Community contribution.</description>
    <link>http://mozillatn.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://mozillatn.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeks of Contribution 2016 - QA - Firefox Nightly</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20%&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/assets/MozillTN_WOC_QA.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 21:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016-QA/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016-QA/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeks of Contribution 2016 - SUMO</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20%&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://mozillatn.github.io/assets/SUMO_TN.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 21:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016-SUMO/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016-SUMO/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeks of Contribution 2016 - Localization</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mozillatn.github.io/assets/MozillTN_WOC_L10N.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Weeks of Contribution Localization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 01:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016-L10N/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016-L10N/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeks of Contribution 2016 - FAQ</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Weeks Of Contributions ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016-FAQ/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016-FAQ/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeks of Contribution 2016</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year Mozilla Tamilnadu community contributors started an initiative  called as weeks of contribution. The main aim of this initiative is to bring first time contributors to contribute to Mozilla Community. We really had great impact in this, around 15 new contributors joined our community and helping to grow us very well. Learn those who joined us last year newly and active &lt;a href=&quot;https://viswaprasathks.wordpress.com/2015/09/06/weeks-of-contribution-impact-on-me-community-part-3/&quot;&gt;Weeks of Contribution 2015 Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 17:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Weeks-Of-Contribution-2016/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Add yourself as Author</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;On April 1st MozillaTN community released new version of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mozillatn.github.io/&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;. The main aim of this website is to bring all the community related or contribution related materials at one place. As a first step we have successfully integrated our community blog here. So this website in future will have details like active club in Tamilnadu, how to get started with various contribution areas, details about task force members of Tamilnadu community and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 07:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Add-Yourself-As-Author/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/Add-Yourself-As-Author/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prasanth is budding FSA started contribution with Localization</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Please introduce yourself and give us three keywords that would define you the best.&lt;img class=&quot;  wp-image-560 alignright&quot; src=&quot;/assets/prashantj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prashantj&quot; width=&quot;380&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is P.Prasanth.I am studying 2nd year BE Computer Science and Engineering in Sri Krishna College of Engineering and Technology, Coimbatore. A passionate programmer , An active social media user and a kind of a person who always look forward for an opportunity to meet new people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) What area are you from [city]?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am from Madurai. But staying in Coimbatore as I am studying here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) What do you do as a career [job/school/retired]?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) List a favorite hobby or something about yourself that you&#39;d like to share.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearing musics,reading books, blogging are my hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Links to your website, blog, etc.?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Blog :-    &lt;a href=&quot;http://foxprasanth.github.io/&quot;&gt;http://foxprasanth.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) How did you discover the Web?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my childhood,it was my elder sister, who introduced me to web, by calling me to accompany her, whenever she went to internet cafes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) How did you hear about Mozilla and Mozilla Tamilnadu Community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard about Mozilla during a tech meetup in Madurai. I was introduced to Mozilla TamilNadu Community by Gautham Venkat, a fellow FSA from Amritha University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8) How and why did you start contributing to Mozilla?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started in localisation event which took place during inauguration of MozMadurai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started contributing to Mozilla because I felt that such contribution would have a great positive impact me. As I felt , I have grown my skills over the past months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10) What’s the contribution you’re the most proud of?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best contribution that I made is “The privacy campaign” which I conducted in my college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11) What advice would you give to someone who is new and interested in contributing to Mozilla?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common problem faced by the begineers is hesitation to mingle. Never hesitate to ask doubts. Because with each doubts , we get each new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12) If you had one word or sentence to describe Mozilla, what would it be?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will describe Mozilla as “the best community for learning and teaching as well!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13) What exciting things do you envision for you and Mozilla in the future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see Mozilla community growing in a rapid pace. With more events coming up, more contributions generated, there comes more innovation. Mozilla will strive hard to keep the Web open and I could see myself helping for it’s great cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14) Is there anything else you&#39;d like to say or add to the above questions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing more.Start working today! and make a better tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15) Please tell us more about your community. Is there anything you find particularly interesting or special about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speciality of Mozilla TamilNadu community is it active participation and its nature to help new FSAs and guide them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16) What’s your best memory with your fellow community members?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best event is the localization event by Gautham @MozspaceMadurai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://foxprasanth.github.io/events/2015/12/21/MozMdu-inaugration/&quot;&gt;http://foxprasanth.github.io/events/2015/12/21/MozMdu-inaugration/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 17:06:46 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/contributor%20post/prasanth-is-budding-fsa-started-contribution-with-localization/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/contributor%20post/prasanth-is-budding-fsa-started-contribution-with-localization/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing My First Extension (Firefox Add-ons)</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In last post I was writing about &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Getting Started with WebExtension&lt;/a&gt;. Its very exicting to learn something new in Web each and everyday. And as a developer the feel when we know our software (General term you can replace with WebExtension)  is going to reach many users its awesome feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 07:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/clubs/Writing-My-First-Extension/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/clubs/Writing-My-First-Extension/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lets Learn about Mozilla Products on Womens Day</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The New Social Media team our MozillaTN has came up with interesting idea to share more information about Mozilla Products and Open source Products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 8th, yes on Women&#39;s day they will sharing question about various Mozilla Products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They will be posting question in both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/MozillaTN/?ref=hl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and also to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mozillatn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can simply reply to the post they make, at the end of the week the results will be announced. We will be finding the top 3 Women Contributors who have awesome knowledge about Mozilla Products. So keep eye on Facebook and twitter profiles between 10.00 AM and 10.00 PM on 8th March&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 20:12:57 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/contest/lets-learn-about-mozilla-products-on-womens-day/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/contest/lets-learn-about-mozilla-products-on-womens-day/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Makilan is Mechanical Engineering student with passion to take web at Remote Places</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;  wp-image-539 alignright&quot; src=&quot;/assets/makilan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;makilan&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;1) Please introduce yourself and give us three keywords that would define you the best.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m Selva Makilan, doing Mechanical Engineering at SASTRA University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can and I will.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovative thinker and Dreamer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) What area are you from [city]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native: Avinangudi, Cuddalore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently in Thanjavur.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) What do you do as a career [job/school/retired]?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student / SASTRA University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) List a favorite hobby or something about yourself that you&#39;d like to share.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hobbies are making Crafts, Popupology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobography (Mobile Photography), Music, Dance Lover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Links to your website, blog, etc.?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC: Selva_Makilan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://m.facebook.com/selva.m.mech.35?ref=bookmarks&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/selva_makilan&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/selva-makilan-9a1580105?trk=hp-identity-name&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/selva_makilan/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/138226376@N08/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/111857443512570695288/posts&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) How did you discover the Web?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Through my family and friends. Well, it all started with creating mail then got associated with the web as such.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) How did you hear about Mozilla and Mozilla Tamilnadu Community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my University, I attended an orientation. In the orientation, one of my seniors took the session about Mozilla and its Contributing areas. After that orientation, I came to my room and searched about Firefox Student Ambassador. Then I saw one Mozcafe event which was conducted by D.Vigneshwar in Thanjavur. I attended the session and then joined the Mozilla Tamil Nadu community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;8) How and why did you start contributing to Mozilla?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, I like to learn something new apart from my academics and improve my skills by those concerns, I  joined in Mozilla then became a Mozilla FSA. It’s really pretty cool to get some ideas. Before entering into Mozilla I didn’t have much knowledge in Computer Science and by contributing in Mozilla Localization Service and done with great Success, I am in a great hope to contribute in other areas and now I am interested in Mozilla L10N.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9) What’s the contribution you’re the proudest of?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secured third place in Tamilnadu in Mozilla Location Service(MLS) is my proudest moment as of now as it is my first contributing area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10) What advice would you give to someone who is new and interested in contributing to Mozilla?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free with Mozilla Community, don’t feel shy to ask anything. Language doesn’t matter and your basic knowledge is enough to do everything because here you have a chance to learn a lot. Community members are always ready to help you anytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11) If you had one word or sentence to describe Mozilla, what would it be?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply Awesome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12) What exciting things do you envision for you and Mozilla in the future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I concentrate on developing this Mozilla community in remote areas, due to less awareness in rural areas we are in the position to improve there also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13) Is there anything else you&#39;d like to say or add to the above questions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I feel these questions are more than enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14) Please tell us more about your community. Is there anything you find particularly interesting or special about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said before, here after my community will be improved in rural areas. Since after coming to a reputed University, I got a chance to know about Mozilla, before that I know Mozilla Firefox as a browser alone, I wasn’t aware of these things behind Mozilla and really am amazed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15) What’s your best memory of your fellow community members?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I joined in a Mozilla community, I didn’t know anything about it, what I have to do, which area would suit me I confused a lot and assumed myself that I am not fit for these things. Then a guy Gowtham encouraged me and helped me a lot. Representatives gave some ideas to do my basic steps for creating a blog, manage a GitHub etc...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 18:10:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/contributor%20spotlight/makilan-is-mechanical-engineering-student-with-passion-to-take-web-at-remote-places/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mozillatn.github.io/blog/contributor%20spotlight/makilan-is-mechanical-engineering-student-with-passion-to-take-web-at-remote-places/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>